http://www.soroptimisteurope.org/terms-of-use-privacy-policy/

Introduction
This Privacy and Cookie Policy (hereinafter “Policy”) explains how Soroptimist International of Europe (hereinafter ‘SIE’), collects, uses and processes personal data related to:
– the users of soroptimisteurope.org (hereinafter “website”); and
– those who make use of other SIE services, whether or not online, which includes contacting SIE via the contact form on the website, e-mail, telephone or other means of communication (hereinafter “You”).
Personal data (hereinafter “data”) contains any information relating to you as a natural person – even when there can only be indirect identification.
SIE cares about the protection of your privacy. SIE therefore treats and protects your data in a lawful, adequate and transparent manner.
The collection and processing of personal data are governed by strict conditions, enforced by the law. While processing your data, SIE acts in accordance with the EU’s General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 of 27 April 2016 concerning the protection of personal data (known as “GDPR”), or any amendment to them. More information concerning data protection can be obtained at the local Data Protection Authority or at the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner.
SIE kindly invites you to read this policy carefully in order to fully understand the way SIE handles your personal data.
The visit and use of our website implies your explicit acceptance (by sharing your data, or by opt-in) with this Policy. Meaning that you agree with the way SIE processes your personal data.
This Policy can be updated from time to time. The most recent version of the Policy will be available on the website. You will be informed through the normal means of communication when significant changes have been made.
Who is the data controller?
SIE takes responsibility of your personal data as a “data controller”. The specific company data are the following:
Soroptimist International of Europe
72, route de Florissant
1206 Geneva, Switzerland
Telephone: +41 (0)22 346 08 80
E-mail: siehq@soroptimisteurope.org
SIE is therefore your interlocutor and accountable to pass on your data to the competent authorities.
SIE can rely upon specialized service providers to process your personal data on behalf of SIE in accordance with this Policy. Only those data which are clearly required will be given to these companies (hereinafter: ‘Processors of SIE’).
Which categories of data are processed by SIE?
SIE can process data and information that have been issued by you, by local clubs or provided by third parties, insofar as these are necessary or useful for the functioning of SIE.
In order to inform you as best as possible, this Policy contains an overview of the categories of personal data that can be processed (this overview is not exhaustive; other kinds of personal data can be processed if necessary). The context in which personal data are collected or processed will be given in this overview. This overview should be read together with the description of the purposes for which SIE processes personal data.
Category
Examples
Context
1/ Website Visitor Data
IP address, page view, time on the website, used device.
This information is gathered when making use of our website.
2/ Contact Details
Name, e-mail address, telephone number
These can be provided by you when contacting us via e-mail, the contact form on our website or by post.
3/ Job Applicants Details
Name, e-mail address, nationality, work experience, address, telephone number
The applicant’s details are kept by saving his or her cv.
4/ Sponsor Details
(Company)Name, address, telephone number
These can be provided by you when a donation is made.
5/ Social Media Data
Your LinkedIn Profile, the messages you send to us through Facebook
When you like our Facebook page or post, or send us a message through LinkedIn.
7/ Cookies
Data on clicking and viewing behaviour of the user, devices of the user, IP-address, type of internet browser, type operating system or preferences.
This information is gathered by means of cookies. More on cookies in Article IX.
SIE does not process data that reveal race or ethnic background, or political beliefs, religious beliefs, membership of a trade union, sexual orientation, genetic or biometric data or medical data.
For which purposes does SIE process your personal data?
SIE collects and processes your personal information for the following purposes. SIE makes sure that only data necessary and relevant for these purposes are processed.
Category
Processing Purposes
1/ Website Visitor Data
Inclusion of personal data in anonymous statistics for internal use, from which the identity of specific persons or companies cannot be ascertained, with the legitimate interests of SIE as a legal basis to continually improve its website and services.
2/ Contact Details
Contact details are used to answer and reply to your e-mails, calls and letters and provide you requested information for the purposes of executing the contract.
3/ Job Applicant Details
Job applicant details are used for the purposes of assessing a candidacy for current or future recruitment.
4/ Sponsor Details
Sponsor details are used for the purpose of executing the sponsor contract.
5/ Social Media Data
Information we collect from our social media channels in order to follow up on any messages or requests directed to us.
7/ Cookies
Infra Article IX.
SIE may process your personal electronic contact information (i.e. your e-mail address) to send you information via newsletters. In this case, SIE first asks for your specific permission.
With whom does SIE share your personal data?
SIE handles your data with the utmost care and will not disclose your data to third parties, unless necessary for the performance of its assignment or to optimize the service of SIE.
For the aforementioned purposes, SIE can disclose your personal data to the following receivers:
– Third parties who assist SIE in the execution, management and control of its activities and services, for example with the IT security and infrastructure of SIE.
These third parties may only use the data for the aforementioned purposes. Any other use is not included and is forbidden. These third parties are contractual obliged to only use your data according to the provisions of this Policy.
SIE will never provide your personal data to other third parties, unless there is prior permission and SIE entered into a contract with this third party containing guaranties concerning the protections of your data.
Furthermore it is possible that, if obliged to do so on the basis of a statutory provision or court order, SIE will disclose your data to the competent authorities.
In the context of these exceptions, SIE shall attempt to inform you prior to the transfer of data. However, because of technical, juridical or commercial reasons, this cannot be guaranteed.
SIE stores your personal data within the EEA, in France.
How long will SIE hold your data?
Data will be stored and processed for the period obligated or justified by law or another legal requirement. If this period is shorter than necessary for the aforementioned purposes, SIE will use the following periods:
Category
Duration of processing
1/ Website Visitor Data
During the duration of your visit to our website. Hereafter your data will be included in anonymous statistics, from which the identity of specific persons or companies cannot be traced.
2/ Contact Details
Contact details are stored for the duration of the relationship and a subsequent duration of 5 years.
3/ Job Applicant Details
Job applicant details are used during recruitment and are stored for the duration of the 2-year procedure and stored for the duration of 3 years after the recruitment phase has been terminated.
4/ Sponsor Details
Sponsor details are used for the duration of the sponsor activities and the subsequent 5 years.
5/ Social Media Data
Information obtained from social media activities is used for the duration of the relationship between SIE and you, and the subsequent 5 years.
7/ Cookies
Infra Article IX.
Security of personal data
SIE applies strict standards to protect the personal data under its control against unauthorized or unlawful processing and against unintentional loss, destruction or damage.
SIE therefore takes technical and organizational measures such as firewalls, SSL certificate and IP restriction, to prevent and detect inappropriate access, loss or disclosure of your personal data.
In the unlikely and unfortunate case that your personal data under the control of SIE are compromised by a breach of information security, SIE will immediately act to identify the cause of such breach and take action through appropriate remedial measures. If necessary, SIE will inform you, as well as the competent data protection authority, of this incident in accordance with the applicable legislation.
In order to process your personal data, we grant access to your personal data to our employees. We guarantee a similar level of protection by making contractual obligations enforceable against the employees and/or appointees. These obligations are similar to those of this Policy.
Your rights as a data subject
Right of access, rectification, erasure, portability of data and right to object
For the purposes mentioned above you have:
– Right of access to your personal data. This means that you can ask SIE whether it processes your personal data, for what purposes these data are processed, which categories of data are processed, and to whom they are communicated.
– A right to rectification if you think your personal details are incorrect or incomplete.
– A right to erase your personal data. At the end of the contract that you have concluded with SIE, you have the right to ask us to stop using your data. SIE may, however, in the context of this declaration, keep track of the personal data required for the purpose of proof of transactions. Under this right to erase, you also have the right to ask SIE at any time to stop using your personal data that are being processed on the basis of your permission or the legitimate interest of SIE. Due to its legitimate interests, SIE can still process your personal data after balancing your interests with that of SIE, unless you decide to terminate the relationship with SIE;
– A right of portability of data that you have provided to SIE if your personal data are processed based on an agreement or on the basis of your permission to send electronic communications and these personal data are processed by means of automated processes. Under this right you can ask SIE to send your own personal data to yourself or to another data processing officer, as far as this is technically possible for SIE.
– You have the right to object to the processing of your data for the purposes stated in Article IV.4. In this event, SIE will stop processing your personal data, unless SIE invokes compelling, justified and heavier weighing grounds for processing that outweigh your interests, rights and freedoms, or for instituting, exercising or substantiating a legal claim.
Exercise of your rights
You can exercise your rights by sending a written request by mail, which is dated, signed and attached with a copy of your identity card (only the front) to privacy@soroptimisteurope.org, via the contact form on our website, or via the ‘unsubscribe’ button at the bottom of our newsletters.
You can also submit a complaint to the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner, per post to Feldeggweg 1, CH-3003 Berne, Switzerland
per e-mail to info@edoeb.admin.ch
per telephone to +41 (0)58 462 43 95
Or to your local European Data Protection Authority.
Cookies
What is a cookie?
A “cookie” is a small text file that is sent from the server of SIE and is stored on your computer’s hard drive. This way we can remember your preferences when visiting our website. The information stored through these cookies can only be read by SIE and only for the duration of your visit to the website.
Why do we use cookies?
Our website primarily uses cookies and similar technologies to enhance the surfing experience on our website. All data SIE retrieves from their cookies are only used to distinguish your preferences from those of the other users of our website. This allows us to offer you a better experience when you visit our website and to optimize our website.
As a result of recent amendments to the law, all websites focusing on certain parts of the European Union are obligated to ask for your permission to use or save cookies and similar technologies on your computer or mobile devices. This Policy clearly and completely informs you about the cookies we use and their purpose.
Kind of cookies:
Cookies can be subdivided based on their offspring, function and durability.
Our website only uses the following cookies:
Functionality cookies
Name
Function
Authentication cookies
‘Remember me’
Identification of the website user.
Language Display cookies
Stores a language preference for the website
For cookies set by third parties (Google Analytics) we kindly refer you to the statements provided by these parties on their respective websites. Please note that we do not have any influence on the content of these statements nor on the content of the cookies of these third parties:
Your permission:
When you first visit our website, you express your implicit approval to accept our different kinds of cookies.
You can block cookies by activating your browser settings which allows you to refuse the cookies. The rejection of these cookies may have the effect of not allowing you to use some functionalities of the website.
Applicable law and jurisdiction
GDPR applies to this Policy, unless Swiss law offers more protection. Any disputes arising from this Policy or otherwise related to this website and/or any of the services provided by SIE will be submitted to the competent court of Geneva.
Questions or requests?
If you have any questions or requests about this Policy, please contact:
Soroptimist International of Europe
72, route de Florissant
1206 Geneva, Switzerland
Telephone: +41 (0)22 346 08 80
E-mail: siehq@soroptimisteurope.org
Soroptimist International
Soroptimist International of Great Britain & Ireland
Soroptimist International of South West Pacific
Soroptimist International of The Americas
By continuing to use the site, you agree to the use of cookies. more information AcceptThe cookie settings on this website are set to "allow cookies" to give you the best browsing experience possible. If you continue to use this website without changing your cookie settings or you click "Accept" below then you are consenting to this.Fermer
